

Ivan Stefanov

Software engineer

Highly motivated software engineer with significant experience in research and development of **critical OSS systems with high load** that scales to multiple servers to provide quality service for **thousands of subscribers**.

One of my strengths is to investigate new technologies that can help me solve problems related with the systems I'm developing. My last efforts are aimed at integration of Google's Golang in the development process and rewriting of some of the most critical systems.

Interests:

- Development of fault tolerant systems;
- Development of systems that should scale well to multiple servers;
- Processing and storing of large data sets with the most modern tools;
- Analysis and optimization of systems that can process hundreds of requests per second;
- Analysis and design of algorithms;

PROFILE

FULL NAME

Ivan Metodiev Stefanov

BORN

02 Aug 1990 - Veliko Tarnovo, Bulgaria

PHONE

EMAIL

ivan_stefanov@ymail.com

FIND ME ON

(https://github.com/FeNoMeNa)

in (https://bg.linkedin.com/pub/ivan-stefanov/68/483/830)

EDUCATION

INFORMATION SECURITY

m Veliko Tarnovo University (Master's Degree) - Graduation June 2015

It covers cryptography, network-based security threats and vulnerabilities, and practical solutions to system and network security. It also includes some advanced security topics such as cloud computing security, wireless security and e-commerce security.

COMPUTER SCIENCE

m Veliko Tarnovo University (Bachelor's Degree) - Graduation June 2013

It covers fundamentals of computer programming, introduction to computer networks, design and analysis of efficient algorithms, data structure representations and their use. It also includes topics such as operating systems and memory management.

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

m "Vela Blagoeva" High School - Graduation May 2009

Intensive learning of mathematics, informatics and foreign languages which prepares students for the software industry. The program covers topics such as computer programming, artificial intelligence and computer security.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TAXIME

Full Stack Software Engineer - Aug 2019 - Current

As a software engineer in TaxiMe, my main goal is to develop and support the core microservices in the company. This includes backend and frontend development with the most modern tools such as Golang, MongoDB, Docker, K8s, ReactJS, etc.

CLOUWAY

■ Head of Software Development - Feb 2015 - Aug 2019

As a team leader of the OSS team, my main goal is to achieve higher productivity for the company by appropriate motivation of the team members and helping them with my experience. I think that the team leader is responsible to find the next leaders.

CLOUWAY

Software Engineer - Feb 2013 - Feb 2015

As a software engineer in the OSS team, my main responsibly was to develop and maintain high scalable servers that provide quality service for thousands of subscribers. Some of the implemented protocols include: dhcp, radius, snmp, cwmp, oauth as well as number of supporting daemons such as proxy servers, logging servers, load balancers, etc.

ACHIEVEMENTS

3RD PRIZE, NATIONAL STUDENT PROGRAMMING CONTEST

★ Bourgas, Bulgaria - 2012

Captain of the VTU team. National Student Programming Contest is an annual multi-tiered competitive programming competition among the universities in Bulgaria.

1ST PRIZE, VTU PROGRAMMING CONTEST

★ Veliko Tarnovo, Bulgaria - 2012

Veliko Tarnovo University Programming Contest is an annual multi-tiered competitive programming competition among the students in the university.

3RD PRIZE, REGIONAL NETWORKING CONTEST

★ Veliko Tarnovo, Bulgaria - 2008

Powered by Cisco. The Regional Networking competitions are a great opportunity for students to showcase their networking abilities and learn valuable new IT skills.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Java 90%

Golang	90%
JavaScript	80%
C++	50%
C	50%
PROGRAMMING SKILLS	
Test Driven Development	90%
Agile Methodologies	90%
Scrum	90%
Algorithms and Data Structures	90%
Scalable Architecture	85%
Cloud Computing	85%
NETWORKING SKILLS	
TCP/IP	90%
НТТР	90%
DHCP	85%
RADIUS	85%
TR-069	85%
SNMP	85%
TOOLS AND FRAMEWORKS	
MongoDB	90%
React & Redux	90%
Git	90%
Docker	80%

MySQL 80%

PostgreSQL 80%

PROJECTS

OAUTH 2.0 SERVER

github.com/FeNoMeNa/experimental-auth (https://github.com/FeNoMeNa/experimental-auth)

A standards compliant OAuth 2.0 authorization server written in Java which makes working with OAuth 2.0 trivial. The server is tested with the most popular OAuth 2.0 clients.

GOHA

github.com/FeNoMeNa/goha (https://github.com/FeNoMeNa/goha)

GOHA is designed to be the simplest way possible to make authorized http requests. It's a HTTP client supporting Basic and Digest access authentication written in Go.

CWMP-PROXY

github.com/FeNoMeNa/cwmp-proxy (https://github.com/FeNoMeNa/cwmp-proxy)

A CWMP proxy, written in Go that will provide you the ability to place CPEs and ACS servers in different networks. Another important feature is the internal load balancing functionality that will distribute the incoming requests to the backend servers.



"UNIX is very simple, it just needs a genius to understand its simplicity." **Dennis Ritchie**